According to the Associated Press, more than 100 Congolese women report being sexually assaulted
in 2019 by staffers of the World Health Organization. The WHO responded by giving
them each $250, but get this, the victims had to work for it. I got my hands on the report from the
independent commission that investigated the alleged abuses that occurred during the 2019
Ebola outbreak in Congo. The investigators interviewed 63 female and 12 male victims
ranging in age from 13 to 43. One woman known as Nadira reported this experience,
To get ahead in the job, you had to have sex. Everyone had sex in exchange for something.
I was even offered sex if I wanted to get a basin of water to wash myself.
Julianne, who was the youngest of the alleged victims, shared that she was selling phone
recharge cards on the side of the road when she was approached by a WHO driver who offered her a
ride home. Instead, he took her to a hotel, assaulted her, and a pregnancy resulted. And I'm absolutely
certain $250 to recover the cost of a child. Now, to receive the cash, the victims had to complete
training courses intended to help them start income generating activities. The Associated Press
stated that this approach was because the UN needed to circumvent its stated policy that it doesn't pay
reparations. Which is interesting because not only does that create a breeding ground for abuses,
but also, hasn't the UN been encouraging the US government to start providing reparations to
descendants of enslaved people? So you telling folks to do stuff you're not willing to do yourself?
That's weird.